<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ios | Emiaostein‘s Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://cszwdy.github.io/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cszwdy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-11T17:43:44+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://cszwdy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Emiaostein]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[排版设计的基础知识（一）]]></title>
    <link href="http://cszwdy.github.io/blog/2013/11/11/typographical-concepts/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-11T10:23:58+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://cszwdy.github.io/blog/2013/11/11/typographical-concepts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://imageblogemiaostein.qiniudn.com/Emiaostein_Blog_paibanshejiyi_Cover.png" alt="Cover" /></p>

<p>本章介绍了与文字排版相关的一些概念，有助于对文字系统 API 的理解。<!--more--></p>

<p><strong>目录</strong></p>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#characters-glyph">字符（Characters）与 字体（Glyph）</a></li>
  <li><a href="#import-foundationh">import “Foundation.h”</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#typefaces-fonts">字体（Typefaces）与 字型（Fonts）</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#typeface">Typeface</a></li>
          <li><a href="#section">字体和字体簇</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><a href="#text-layout">3. Text Layout</a></li>
      <li><a href="#tips">4. Tips</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="characters-glyph">字符（Characters）与 字体（Glyph）</h2>

<p><strong><code>字符</code></strong> 是书面语言中的最小单位。</p>

<p>&#8220;`ObjC</p>

<h1 id="import-foundationh">import “Foundation.h”</h1>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>(void)p_testMethod {</p>

    <p>for (int i = 0; i &lt; 10; i++) {</p>

    <pre><code>  [self p_testMethod];
  NSLog(@"this is a test");   }
</code></pre>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>}</p>

<p>&#8220;`</p>

<p>字符的表现形式集合称为字型（Glyph）。</p>

<p>Any one of these various concrete forms of a <code>character</code> is called a <code>Glyph</code> .</p>

<p>一些情况下，单个字符可由多个字体组成；另一种情况，单个字体由多个字符组成。后一种情况称为连字（Ligatures）。</p>

<p>In some case a character may be represented by multiple glyphs. In other cases, a single glyph may represent multiple characters,as in the case of a <code>ligature</code>, or joined letter.</p>

<h2 id="typefaces-fonts">字体（Typefaces）与 字型（Fonts）</h2>

<h3 id="typeface">Typeface</h3>
<p>A <code>typeface</code>(also known as font family) is a set of visually related shapes for some or all of the characters in a written language. </p>

<p>from Wikipedia:
a typeface (also known as font family) is a set of one or more fonts each composed of glyphs that share common design features. Each font of a typeface has a specific weight, style, condensation, width, slant, italicization, ornamentation, and designer or foundry (and formerly size, in metal fonts). </p>

<p>A <code>typestyle</code>, or simply style(also called traits), is a distinguishing visual characteristic of a typeface, such as,  such as bold, italic, condensed, expanded, narrow, small caps, poster fonts, and fixed pitch.</p>

<h3 id="section">字体和字体簇</h3>
<p>A <code>font</code> is a series of glyphs depicting the characters in a consistent size, typeface, and typestyle. 
A <code>font family</code> (also known as Typeface) is a group of fonts that share a typeface but differ in typestyle. </p>

<h2 id="text-layout">3. Text Layout</h2>

<p>Text <code>layout</code> is the process of arranging glyphs on a display device, in an area called a text view , which represents an area similar to a page in traditional typesetting. </p>

<p>The order in which glyphs are laid out relative to each other is called text <code>direction</code>. </p>

<p>To create lines from a string of glyphs, the layout engine must perform <code>line breaking</code> by finding a point at which to end one line and begin the next. </p>

<p>The layout manager lays out glyphs along an invisible line called the <code>baseline</code>.</p>

<h2 id="tips">4. Tips</h2>

<p>&#8220;` Text
Characters and glyphs do not have one-to-one correspondence;</p>

<p>&#8220;`</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
